globalsynturf.com 2016-06-06

# Privacy Policy

This privacy notice discloses the privacy practices for Global Syn-Turf.com. This privacy notice applies solely to information collected by this web site. Information Collection, Use, and SharingWe are the sole owners of the information collected on this site. We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily give us via email or other direct contact from you. We will not sell or rent this information to anyone. We will use your information to respond to you or take an orders. We also may collect personally identifiable information that you provide to us, such as your name, address, phone number or email address. We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than as necessary to fulfill your request, e.g. to ship an order. Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email in the future to tell you about specials, new products or services, or changes to this privacy policy. We use technologies like cookies (small files stored by your browser), web beacons, or unique device identifiers to anonymously identify your computer or device so we can deliver a better experience. Our systems also log information like your browser, operating system and IP address. We do not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under 13. If you believe we have inadvertently collected such information, please contact us so we can promptly obtain parental consent or remove the information. To customize our service for you, we may collect and store your precise geographic location as part of your user profile. This data generally is not shared with others. We generally do not share personally identifiable information (such as name, address, email or phone) with other companies for marketing purposes.Your Access to and Control Over InformationYou can sign into your account to see or delete any personally identifiable information we have stored, such as your name, address, email or phone number. You can also contact us by email to request to see or delete this information. You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time. You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the email address or phone number given on our website: See what data we have about you, if any. Change/correct any data we have about you. Have us delete any data we have about you. Express any concern you have about our use of your data. We don't share your information with third parties.Ad TrackingWe do not allow advertising companies to collect data through our service for ad targeting. SecurityWe take reasonable administrative, physical and electronic measures designed to safeguard and protect your information from unauthorized access or disclosure. This includes utilizing Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts the personal information you input, and storing your information in encrypted form behind a firewall designed to block access from outside our network. However, no security or encryption method can be guaranteed to protect information from hackers or human error. br /> Information we collect may be stored or processed on computers located in any country where we do business. ContactIf you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policies, please contact us: Contact Us To operate the service, we also may make identifiable and anonymous information available to third parties in these limited circumstances: (1) with your express consent, (2) when we have a good faith belief it is required by law, (3) when we have a good faith belief it is necessary to protect our rights or property, or (4) to any successor or purchaser in a merger, acquisition, liquidation, dissolution or sale of assets. Your consent will not be required for disclosure in these cases, but we will attempt to notify you, to the extent permitted by law to do so. This privacy policy was last updated on February 7, 2014. Our privacy policy may change from time to time. If we make any material changes to our policies, we will place a prominent notice on our website or application. If the change materially affects registered users, we will send a notice to you by email, push notification or text.

#### [Global Syn-Turf at Watersavers Irrigation's Demo Day](http://www.globalsynturf.com/b/watersavers-demoday/1060/)

Global Syn-Turf, Inc., the world's largest manufacturer and supplier of artificial grass, participated in Watersavers Irrigation's Demo Day on April 3rd. The event took place at one of Watersavers Irrigation's warehouse stores. More than 100 Northern California irrigation and green industry professionals and consumers attended the event to test out the latest irrigation systems and landscaping supplies, and listen to presentations from top supply manufacturers. "We've been selling artificial grass products for years now, so even before the event we had established ourselves in the region," said Rachel Brady, Global Syn-Turf's sales and marketing manager. "However, ever since California's water crisis, and now Jerry Brown's announcement of mandatory water restrictions, we've become the definitive regional experts on artificial grass in California. We're receiving an unprecedented amount of interest from local contractors and municipalities who want to test our products." With more than 95 gallons of water per day wasted on outdoor uses per household, consumers, contractors and dealers stand to benefit from artificial grass's advantages. According to ms. Brady, Global Syn-Turf has the power to fundamentally transform the culture of the irrigation and green industries by making it easy for people to have a perfectly lush, verdant lawn without consuming precious resources. The Global Syn-Turf team was on hand at the event to present the company's latest artificial grass innovations,

#### [Global Syn-Turf Introduced Latest Synthetic Grass Technology at 47th Annual NSLGA Professional Turf, Plant & Tree Conference](http://www.globalsynturf.com/b/press-release-global-syn-turf-introduced-latest-synthetic-grass-technology-at-47th-annual-nslga-professional-turf-plant-tree-conference/952/)

  Global Syn-Turf, Inc., the green industry's premier artificial grass supplier and manufacturer, has confirmed that its products were showcased at the 47th Annual Professional Turf, Plant & Tree Conference, hosted by the Nassau Suffolk Landscape Gardeners Association (NSLGA). NSLGA's most comprehensive conference of the year, the event took place February 24 at the Nassau Veterans Memorial Coliseum in Uniondale, New York.   At the conference, around 3,000 decision-makers from around the country gathered for one day of educational seminars and courses and an exhibit hall which showcased more than 200 vendor booths. The annual event serves as an opportunity for green industry professionals to learn new strategies to improve their businesses. Global Syn-Turf's products on display showcased how the green industry -- comprising landscapers, golf courses, arborists, municipalities, schools, etc. -- can save time and money on maintenance, manage labor costs more effectively, and optimize their grounds' playability more easily with the company's artificial grass products.  "Exhibiting at the Professional Turf, Plant & Tree Conference offered a great opportunity to show green industry professionals how Global Syn-Turf can help improve their business with clients. We were excited to be a part of it this year," says Bruce Lamb, Territory Sales Manager, East Coast.

#### [The Prehistory of Artificial Grass](http://www.globalsynturf.com/b/the-prehistory-of-artificial-grass/949/)

  When one thinks of artificial grass, the image that comes to mind is that of a lush, verdant yard with plastic fibers or an artificial grass soccer field at their local park. But that hasn't always been the case. In fact, according to a simple Google Search, the phrase "artificial grass" goes all the way back to the 18thcentury, when it had a different meaning. Back then, according to a monthly journal first published in 1861 called Evans's Rural Economist, artificial grass was any grass which required an art to grow (or any grass which required a "green thumb"). According to the journal, "Botanists restrict the term 'grass' to the natural order Graminea; but common observers, and even agricultural writers, in this country, apply the term 'artificial grass' to clovers and lucern, as well also as to timothy, and such grasses proper as require cultivation, restricting the term 'natural grass' to such grasses proper as naturally take possession without artificial seeding." This definition is very different than the meaning of today. Today, on the contrary, artificial grass refers to a synthetic grass surface which doesn't require a green thumb, art, or cultivation at all -- because synthetic grass doesn't grow! It is unclear when the change in meaning occurred, but most likely it started with the introduction artificial

#### [Global Syn-Turf: Giving Back to the Fort Worth Community](http://www.globalsynturf.com/b/global-syn-turf-giving-back-to-fort-worth-community/1213/)

We are thrilled to be a part of a future of Fort Worth, Texas! The park on Magnolia and Henderson is one of its kind parks in the United States, created by efforts of local enthusiasts and thousands of people in the community. Two weeks ago, it was just a vacant lot left alone for future development. Today, it's a beautiful small oasis for individuals and families to take a break and get together to talk, play and enjoy outdoors. Fort Worth, Texas has more than 270 city parks, and according to Open Space Master Plan signed in 2015 by the City of Fort Worth Parks and Community Services Department envisions to restore and maintain the viability of the park, recreation, and open space systems, provide new parkland to meet recreational needs in developing areas of the city, and improve the variety of park and open space opportunities available to the community. But there are small empty places throughout the city that can be transformed into restful islands, the monument of community efforts, just like the Magnolia Park. This park is created 100 percent by donated materials and build by local companies and community members. Colorful blue containers are neatly

#### [NEW! Global Syn-Turf Exclusive Cashmere Collection of Artificial Grass](http://www.globalsynturf.com/b/global-syn-turf-new-and-exclusive-cashmere-collection-of-artificial-grass/1212/)

Spring may have many people racing for the barbecue grills, family picnics, and a butterfly watching on a Sunday morning; there are as just as many who hanker after the invigorating qualities of brisker temperatures: bolstering hikes and windswept adventures, all followed by a mad dash back to the backyard to play and enjoy a cup of coffee. Inspired by this love of America's great outdoors, Global Syn-Turf Cashmere collection comprises everything needed to combine style and softness with cushy, delicate multi-color fiber to adapt a native beauty of soft, lush, evergreen grass. Featuring color combinations of ever-stylish field and olive green, the Cashmere collection works effortlessly together to echo the deeper colors of the changing season while ensuring never fading greens that will add warmth and cheer to bleak days and dull weather. With a distinctly natural feel, the collection employs synthetic grass fibers that have been produced to exceed governmental standards in quality and environmental benefits lending a traditional touch to the modern landscape. The emphasis on texture creates a look that's as well suited to the long hours and sophisticated pace of city life worked off by aimless walks through changing fields. Those on the endless quest for the Holy Grail of artificial grass - the perfect multi-colored fibers with double thatching to

#### [Can Drought Steal The American Dream?](http://www.globalsynturf.com/b/can-drought-steal-the-american-dream/1209/)

The state of Califonia is currently in its fifth year of severe drought. Despite Governor Brown's declaration of a state drought emergency in 2014, Californias fell short of the mandated water conservation target. Residents used 23.9 percent less water in 2014 compared to 2013. Official call is an "enormous effort" is saving water despite missed target. Saved water in the nine months period is enough for nearly six million people for one year. Even though El Nino delivered a near-average amount of precipitations and snow in some areas of the state, Southern California saw relatively weak year of rain, leaving most reservoirs low. Any changes to the emergency conservation order will take effect in June 2016. During times of drought, plants and vegetation dry, stream and river flow decline, the water level in reservoirs, lakes and wells fall. As drought persists, long-term impact will emerge, land subsidence, seawater intrusion, and damage to the ecosystem. It can cause the land to sink due to excessive groundwater pumping and aquifer depletion. Seawater intrusion in coastal communities compromises groundwater quality. Water allocations for river, wildlife, wetland and fish restoration projects can be stopped or reduced. A single spark can start wildfires in
